# DenysPotapov

PHP developer

#### contact

+38 050 330-20-57
 denys.potapov
 in denyspotapov
denys.potapov@gmail.com

#### **PHP skills**

Phalcon, Silex, MySQL, PHPUnit, codeception, composer, TravisCI

#### front end skills

JavaScript, AngularJs HTML, CSS (SCSS), grunt

#### other skills

git, python, go

#### languages

bilingual Ukrainian/Russian intermediate English basic German

## profile

I am a developer with over 9 years experience working on a variety of projects from conception to delivery. I am conversant in a wide range of technologies, now focused on PHP web development, follow the latest industry trends with great interest (OOP, PSR, SCSS, HTML5). My approach is methodical but creative. I am comfortable working either independently or as part of a team.

#### education

2002–2008 **M.Sc. degree in Computer Science**Specialisation in computer systems and robotics

## **experience**

2012—Present	<b>barzo.com.ua</b> Creating and launching a start-up company. Developing from the ground e-commerce platform (PHP, MySql, HTML, SCSS). Working with and managing team of 3 freelancers.
2012—Present	<b>Qport</b> Creating a large network of digital signage systems (biggest project with 8000 screens). Integrating ERP system in retail stores (15 stores).
2009—2012	<b>Qport</b> Developing interactive screens software (python). Developing an ERP system for retail stores (1c ERP).
2008—2009	<b>Physico-technological institute</b> Development and integration of foundry process modelling system (Object Pascal) for perspective developments department institute of metals and alloys of the National academy of science of Ukraine
2005—2007	Proling Office developer

### awards

August 2014	IQLab Challenge PHP back end development	2 <sup>nd</sup> place
November 2013	<b>UA Web Challenge V</b> Back end development	3 <sup>rd</sup> place
	<b>Codingame oDesk Contest</b> python developers	5 <sup>th</sup> place

online version (ASP.NET)

Development of machine translation system ProlingOffice (C#) and it's

#### skills

advanced PHP back end developement

• Modern PHP frameworks (Phalcon, Silex);

• SQL (MySQL, PDO);

• Code testing (PHPUnit, codeception);

• Continuous integration (composer, TravisCI);

• Version control systems (git, git-flow).

intermediate front end skills

JavaScript, AngularJs, HTML, CSS (SCSS), grunt

basic **python, go** 

## languages

native Russian/Ukrainian

intermediate **English** conversationally fluent

basic German basic words and phrases only

# community

blogging habrahabr.ru

Top-100 author in biggest Russian-speaking IT community

speaking IT conferences

Taking part in local IT conferences as visor and speaker. ('Object Calis-

thenics in php' at WebCamp Developer Day on youtube).

open source PHP password generator library

Library has 24 stars on github and more then 30 download on packag-

ist

## interests

volunteer Running a code club

Code-club in Kyiv is a part of network of volunteer-led after school cod-

ing clubs for children aged 9-11

running